How to sew a sewing machine
Before we start sewing the finished version, let's learn about the sewing machine tool set.
The sewing machine tool set can be found in 2D window or 3D window.
Their operation is different from each other.
First is the sewing machine tool. It can sew two separate lines together.
Use the sewing machine tool to click the first line, then move the mouse to the second line.
Before creating the sewing machine, please refer to the preview effect to make sure the direction is correct.
After confirming the direction is correct, click the second line and the sewing machine is completed.
The sewing machine tool is to identify the lines that are interrupted by a straight line.
Back to the previous step, now let's learn how to use the sewing machine tool in 3D window.
Click the first line, then click the second line.
The sewing machine tool in 3D and 2D window have no operation difference.
If our direction is the opposite, the sewing machine will cross.
At this time, we can switch to the editing sewing machine tool.
Go to the 2D or 3D window, click the right button on the wrong sewing machine and choose to change the sewing machine.
Now the sewing machine direction is correct.
If we want a more free sewing machine, please use the free sewing machine tool.
Click the right button, then move the mouse along the direction of the sewing machine.
Click again to finish the selection of the sewing line.
Then go to the second sewing machine and repeat the steps.
Click the right button, then move the mouse along the direction of the sewing machine.
At this time, there will be a blue dot.
The blue dot shows the end point of the sewing line that is equal to the length of the first sewing line.
Click this blue dot to complete the creation of the long sewing line.
After learning the free sewing machine tool, we can try to edit the sewing line.
Use the edit sewing machine tool to drag the end point of the free sewing line to the straight line.
You can also drag the end point of the sewing line to the straight line.
You can also drag the end point of the sewing line to the other side of the sewing line.
When selecting the sewing line, click the right button and select delete sewing in the menu.
Or just press the delete button to delete the sewing line.
Now let's learn how to use the free sewing machine in the 3D window.
Switch to the free sewing machine and click on the 70 points.
Move the mouse in the direction of the sewing line to the end point of the first line.
Double-click the mouse to the left.
Double-click is the end selection command for some of the common functions in the 3D window.
Then repeat the operation and click on the 70 points.
Then double-click on the end point to complete the creation of a set of sewing lines.
Of course, the free sewing machine can also use the straight line as the starting point or the end point.
Here we can see
that the end point of the free sewing machine can be the middle of a line.
And we can use the end point of other sewing lines to complete the sewing line.
Next, let's learn how to sew a line separated by multiple lines together.
I recommend you to create it in the 2D window.
Here we use the line sewing as an example.
Click on the first line in the same way as the previous operation.
Then press the Shift key.
At this time, the color of the sewing line will turn yellow-green.
It means that we are creating a 1 to n sewing line.
Then from left to right, the mouse is close to the left end point.
Click to select two lines.
After completion, release the Shift key and complete the creation.
Don't forget the sewing line in the middle.
Finally, the sewing line between the multiple lines and the multiple lines is created.
First, select the sewing line with the line sewing.
This is the same way of selecting the sewing line.
But we need to follow the order first.
Click on the good side of the line in the direction of the sewing line.
In the process of creating the sewing line,
if there is a mistake, you can press Backspace to return to the previous step.
After completing the selection of the good side,
press the Enter key to complete the selection confirmation.
After confirmation, the first set of sewing lines will turn pure green.
Then please press the sewing direction and order to select the second set of lines.
Press the Enter key again to complete the creation of the sewing line.
Finally, use the line sewing tool with the shortcut key N to create the sewing line between the panels.
Then select the top panel and press the right key to select the frozen panel in the candy window.
The frozen panel will be fixed in the 3D space.
Press the control key to open the simulation.
You can see that the panel is properly sewn and becomes a pinstripe structure.
Go to the file in the upper left corner.
Open the project.
Open the previously saved file.
Select the line sewing tool.
In the 2D window, refer to the effect in the video to complete the sewing line.
First, the sewing line in the front of the panel.
Press the button to sew the two lines together.
Then continue to create the sewing line on the side of the panel.
Then the sewing line between the sleeves and the panel.
Note that the sewing line marks match.
You can also refer to the light blue preview sewing line effect in the 3D window.
Make sure there is no intersection.
Change the perspective.
Check which positions are not sewn.
Sew the sides of the sleeves together.
The golden line can be completed in the 3D window.
It is more convenient to match the sewing line direction.
The front and sleeves are created by matching the panel, panel and sewing line.
The back panel itself is a panel with a left and right symmetry.
Since the panels are in a symmetrical state,
you can see that the sewing line on the other side will be created automatically.
Next, let's create the sewing line of the pocket.
It is more convenient to use the free sewing tool here.
Click the starting point.
Move the mouse along the sewing direction.
Click the end point.
Then go to the inner line of the large body and perform the same operation.
Of course, we can also use the free sewing tool to sew in the 3D window.
Press the control key to return to the previous step of the operation.
The free sewing of the 2D window is a little different.
Because there is a shorter edge in the pocket,
it will automatically select the shorter edge.
Therefore, when we select the free sewing line,
we need to press and hold to confirm the direction of the sewing line.
Double-click to confirm the selection.
Adjust the angle to prevent the panel from blocking and affecting the selection of the sewing line.
Similarly, click the starting point.
Move the mouse along the sewing line and press and hold to confirm the correct direction.
Finally, double-click to complete the creation of this pair of sewing lines.
After the sewing line is completed,
open the simulation.
Here I choose to use the GPU simulation.
For the simulation quality,
select the default normal speed.
After opening the simulation,
the clothing will be influenced by the gravity in the environment and the sewing line,
and will be worn on the virtual model.
In addition to the manual creation of the sewing line,
for the simpler clothing structure,
we can use the automatic sewing function.
The automatic sewing function
will take into account the location and shape of each panel and create the sewing line.
First, change to the ice sewing line tool.
Press Ctrl A to select all the sewing lines,
then press the Delete key to delete them.
Since the pocket does not belong to the body structure part,
we can temporarily delete it first,
and then add it back.
Then go to the 3D tool bar,
select all 3D arrangement positions.
All panels will be arranged around the virtual model before the simulation.
Then you can use the automatic sewing function.
In the window display,
select the type of clothing.
There are clothes, pants and dresses to choose from.
For the different clothing types,
the specific options for the bottom are also different.
The front gold is a closed-door closed-door type.
Here, select closed,
so that the front and middle will be all sewed together.
The front gold is a closed-door closed-door type.
Since there is no collar, you can automatically select the shape of the collar.
Click to confirm that the seam line will be automatically created between the panels.
Rotate the view to check if there is a missing seam line.
Then start the simulation, the clothes will be worn on the virtual model.
Then switch to the adjustment panel tool, select the inner line of the entire pocket, click on the right, select the colon as the panel with the seam line.
After arranging the position between the 2D window and the 3D window separately, use the edit seam line tool to delete the excess seam line.
Select the seam line at the opening, click on the delete button to delete.
Press the control button to start the simulation, the pocket is done.
This is the knowledge about sewing, see you in the next video.